<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-30T13:19:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Copland</title><subtitle>The objective of the Copland project is formally specifing and building tools for remote attestation.  The core Copland language definition provides a formally verified definition of attestation protocols.  Based on the core language, researchers are developing tools for remote attestation including attestation managers, exchange formats, and attestation service providers.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Automated Trust Analysis Paper Accepted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/31/Automated-Trust-Analysis-Paper-Published.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automated Trust Analysis Paper Accepted" /><published>2021-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/31/Automated-Trust-Analysis-Paper-Published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/31/Automated-Trust-Analysis-Paper-Published.html">&lt;p&gt;“Automated Trust Analysis of Copland Specifications for Layered
Attestation” by Paul Rowe, John Ramsdell, and Ian Kretz has been
accepted for publication at &lt;em&gt;Principles and Practice of Declarative
Programming (PPDP’21)&lt;/em&gt;, September 6-8 in Tallinn, Estonia. The paper
describes a method for analyzing trust properties of Copland phrases,
allowing analysts and designers to evaluate the strength of a Copland
phrase in the presence of an active adversary. You can access a prepub
manuscript from the publications page. The full details of inputs used
for examples in the paper can be browsed &lt;a href=&quot;https://copland-lang.org/resources/chase/ppdp/README&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“Automated Trust Analysis of Copland Specifications for Layered Attestation” by Paul Rowe, John Ramsdell, and Ian Kretz has been accepted for publication at Principles and Practice of Declarative Programming (PPDP’21), September 6-8 in Tallinn, Estonia. The paper describes a method for analyzing trust properties of Copland phrases, allowing analysts and designers to evaluate the strength of a Copland phrase in the presence of an active adversary. You can access a prepub manuscript from the publications page. The full details of inputs used for examples in the paper can be browsed here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MEMOCODE Paper Accepted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/30/MEMOCODE-Paper-Accepted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MEMOCODE Paper Accepted" /><published>2021-08-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/30/MEMOCODE-Paper-Accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/08/30/MEMOCODE-Paper-Accepted.html">&lt;p&gt;“Design and Formal Verification of a Copland-based Attestation
Protocol” by Adam Petz, Grant Jurgensen, and Perry Alexander has been accepted for
publication at the &lt;em&gt;MEMOCODE ‘21&lt;/em&gt; conference, Nov 20-22, to be held
virtually. This paper introduces a workflow for both analyzing and executing
Copland-based attestation protocols in the context of a security
architecture.  It concludes by instantiating that workflow with a
concrete architecture and layered attestation protocol
designed for a DARPA CASE demonstration platform that hosts a legacy
UAV flight control application.  Download a pdf of the paper from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ku-sldg.github.io/copland/publications.html&quot;&gt;publications page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“Design and Formal Verification of a Copland-based Attestation Protocol” by Adam Petz, Grant Jurgensen, and Perry Alexander has been accepted for publication at the MEMOCODE ‘21 conference, Nov 20-22, to be held virtually. This paper introduces a workflow for both analyzing and executing Copland-based attestation protocols in the context of a security architecture. It concludes by instantiating that workflow with a concrete architecture and layered attestation protocol designed for a DARPA CASE demonstration platform that hosts a legacy UAV flight control application. Download a pdf of the paper from the publications page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NFM ‘21 (Virtual) Conference Presentation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/28/nfm21-presentation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NFM '21 (Virtual) Conference Presentation" /><published>2021-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/28/nfm21-presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/28/nfm21-presentation.html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Petz recently presented his joint work with Dr. Perry Alexander entitled “An Infrastructure for Faithful
Execution of Remote Attestation Protocols” at the (virtual) &lt;em&gt;NASA
Formal Methods (NFM’21)&lt;/em&gt; conference.  A video recording of the
talk/slides and live Q&amp;amp;A following the talk can be viewed on Youtube
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LJUYM5ALuz0?t=7420&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
  Download a pdf of the paper from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ku-sldg.github.io/copland/publications.html&quot;&gt;publications page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Adam Petz recently presented his joint work with Dr. Perry Alexander entitled “An Infrastructure for Faithful Execution of Remote Attestation Protocols” at the (virtual) NASA Formal Methods (NFM’21) conference. A video recording of the talk/slides and live Q&amp;amp;A following the talk can be viewed on Youtube here. Download a pdf of the paper from the publications page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Copland Collection Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/20/Copland-Collection-Released.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Copland Collection Released" /><published>2021-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/20/Copland-Collection-Released</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/05/20/Copland-Collection-Released.html">&lt;p&gt;Our MITRE colleagues have released The Copland Collection, a collection of tools for processing and analyzing Copland protocol specifications.  The Copland Collection includes application of the CHASE model finder to explore interleaving of corruption and measurements to better understand protocol effectiveness.  Download the Copland Collection &lt;a href=&quot;resources/copland-collection.tgz&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our MITRE colleagues have released The Copland Collection, a collection of tools for processing and analyzing Copland protocol specifications. The Copland Collection includes application of the CHASE model finder to explore interleaving of corruption and measurements to better understand protocol effectiveness. Download the Copland Collection here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NFM Paper Accepted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/NFM-Paper-Accepted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NFM Paper Accepted" /><published>2021-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/NFM-Paper-Accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/02/24/NFM-Paper-Accepted.html">&lt;p&gt;“An Infrastructure for Faithful Execution of Remote Attestation
Protocols” by Adam Petz and Perry Alexander has been accepted for
publication at &lt;em&gt;NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM’21)&lt;/em&gt;, May 24-28, in
Norfolk, VA. This paper presents a verified model of our attestation
manager implementation that compiles Copland terms into an attestation
intermediate form. Download a
prepub manuscript from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ku-sldg.github.io/copland/publications.html&quot;&gt;publications page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“An Infrastructure for Faithful Execution of Remote Attestation Protocols” by Adam Petz and Perry Alexander has been accepted for publication at NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM’21), May 24-28, in Norfolk, VA. This paper presents a verified model of our attestation manager implementation that compiles Copland terms into an attestation intermediate form. Download a prepub manuscript from the publications page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Haskell Attestation Manager Release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/Haskell-Attestation-Manager-Release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Haskell Attestation Manager Release" /><published>2021-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/Haskell-Attestation-Manager-Release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/Haskell-Attestation-Manager-Release.html">&lt;p&gt;Our
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ku-sldg/haskell-am&quot;&gt;Haskell Attestation Manager&lt;/a&gt; is
available. The Haskell Attestation Manger is a direct implementation
of a Copland interpreter using monad transformers. The Haskell AM is
used primarily for prototyping, but can be used for delivered
systems.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our Haskell Attestation Manager is available. The Haskell Attestation Manger is a direct implementation of a Copland interpreter using monad transformers. The Haskell AM is used primarily for prototyping, but can be used for delivered systems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CakeML Attestation Manager Release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/CakeML-Attestation-Manager-Release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CakeML Attestation Manager Release" /><published>2021-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/CakeML-Attestation-Manager-Release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/12/CakeML-Attestation-Manager-Release.html">&lt;p&gt;Our reference
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ku-sldg/am-cakeml&quot;&gt;CakeML Attestation Manager&lt;/a&gt; is
available. The CakeML Attestation Manger is a relatively small
implementation of a Copland interpreter written using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cakeml.org&quot;&gt;CakeML&lt;/a&gt;
language. The implementation is actively maintained and used as our
primary delivery platform.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our reference CakeML Attestation Manager is available. The CakeML Attestation Manger is a relatively small implementation of a Copland interpreter written using the CakeML language. The implementation is actively maintained and used as our primary delivery platform.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorial Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/31/Tutorial-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorial Update" /><published>2020-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/31/Tutorial-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/31/Tutorial-Update.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;resources/tutorial/README&quot;&gt;Copland Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; has
been udpated to include analysis tool outputs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Copland Tutorial has been udpated to include analysis tool outputs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Copland Tutorial Added</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/22/Copland-Tutorial-Added.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Copland Tutorial Added" /><published>2020-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/22/Copland-Tutorial-Added</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/22/Copland-Tutorial-Added.html">&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&quot;resources/tutorial/README&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on
writing basic Copland phrases is available on the
&lt;a href=&quot;documentation.html&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; page.  The 
tutorial describes various attestation styles including mutual attestation,
certificate-style attestation, and delegated appraisal.  Example phrases are
included throughout.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A new tutorial on writing basic Copland phrases is available on the Documentation page. The tutorial describes various attestation styles including mutual attestation, certificate-style attestation, and delegated appraisal. Example phrases are included throughout.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Haskell AM Initial Release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/Haskell-AM-Initial-Release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Haskell AM Initial Release" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/Haskell-AM-Initial-Release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/Haskell-AM-Initial-Release.html">&lt;p&gt;The first release of our Haskell Attestation Manager is now available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ku-sldg.github.io/copland/software.html&quot;&gt;software page&lt;/a&gt;.  Clone the release repo and follow the instructions in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; to build the release.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first release of our Haskell Attestation Manager is now available on the software page. Clone the release repo and follow the instructions in README.md to build the release.</summary></entry></feed>